Guide to the Pare Lorentz papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series X: General, 1914-1994, undated
  - Subseries 4. Writings about Pare Lorentz, 1965-1979
    Includes several dissertations and masters theses on Lorentz, including the various works by Robert Snyder. Also located here is an oral history interview from the 1970s, and Lest We Forget a genealogical pamphlet written by Lorentz’s “aunt” Bess. Some letters are from fifth graders who wrote Lorentz to tell them how much they enjoyed a classroom viewing of The River.
    - A History of the Early Productions of Pare Lorentz and the U.S. Film Service 1935-1940 by Robert L. Snyder, 1965 (Box 182, Folder 3)
    - Final Chapter of Snyder Dissertation, 1965 (Box 182, Folder 4)
    - Films of Merit by Robert Snyder, 1965, (2 Folders) (Box 182, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Letters to Pare Lorentz Commenting on Snyder Dissertation, 1968 (Box 183, Folder 1)
    - The Early Productions of Pare Lorentz by Robert Snyder, 1965 (Box 183, Folder 2)
    - An Analysis of the Visual Portion of the U.S. Documentary Film The River by William Fleming, 1966 (Box 183, Folder 3)
    - The Contextual and Stylistic Relations in the River: A Pare Lorentz Film by Ferne Liverance Galantai, 1979 (Box 183, Folder 4)
    - A Critical Study of The River by Sister Paula Reiten, 1970 (Box 183, Folder 5)
    - Lest We Forget by Bess Lorentz Wade, 1968 (Box 184, Folder 1)
    - Conversations with Pare Lorentz, 1976 (Box 184, Folder 2)
    - West Virginia Hillbilly, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 5. The Days of F.D.R., 1942-1978
    . This subseries contains notes and accounting records related to a proposed project to trace Franklin Roosevelt’s daily movements over the course of his presidency.
    - FDR Day By Day, 1942-1943 (Box 184, Folder 3)
    - Cost Information Concerning The Days of Franklin D. Roosevelt: A Chronicle, 1948-1978, (2 Folders) (Box 184, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Accounting Information, 1947-1978, (2 Folders) (Box 184, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Audit, 1978 (Box 185, Folder 1)
    - Roosevelt Book, 1977-1978 (Box 185, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 6. General, 1941-1974
    These records include a screenplay for the film, Citizen Kane.
    - Screenplay for Citizen Kane, 1941 (Box 185, Folder 3)
    - Paul Strand, 1974 (Box 185, Folder 4)
- Series XI: Digitized Negatives, 1930s, undated.
  This series contains digitized images of negatives from the 1930s. Many are frames from Lorentz’ movies, including the famous “Day Walk/Night Walk” sequences from Fight For Life. Others are still photos taken on set. Some were originally stills taken by photographers from the Farm Security Administration, the Resettlement Administration, and the U.S. Film Service.
  - Digitized Negatives- Access in Repository